Henry Goodman collection of theater playbills, circa 1762 – circa early-1900s, 1951; bulk dates circa 1830s-1865
UCLA Library Special Collections
Henry Goodman collection of theater playbills
Bulk, 1830-1865
circa 1762 – circa early-1900s, 1951; bulk dates, circa 1830s- circa 1865
2286
UCLA Library Special Collections
8.0 linear ft. (1 small flat box, 4 flat boxes, and 3 oversized flat boxes)
Henry Goodman, Ph.D., faculty emeritus at UCLA, had distinguished career as professor of theater. The collection, assembled by Goodman, consists of 18th, 19th, and 20th century British theatre playbills, a small number of American and foreign language playbills, five scrapbooks and a small amount of illustrations.
Goodman, Henry, d. 2012
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7798530
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Professor Henry Goodman.
Biography/History
Henry Goodman was born November 21, 1919 in Minneapolis, Minnesota. Goodman received his BA (1941), MA (1947), and Ph.D. (1952) from the University of Minnesota. From 1953-1956, he taught at Rockford College in Illinois and at Reed College in Oregon. In 1957, Goodman joined the faculty at University of California, Los Angeles, where he taught and directed until his retirement in 1990. Among his many accomplishments, he introduced and directed the world premiere of Bertolt Brecht’s The Caucasian Chalk Circle at Carleton College. Henry Goodman died April 15, 2012 in Los Angeles, California.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of 18th, 19th, and 20th theater playbills and ephemera collected by UCLA professor of theater Henry Goodman. The bulk of the collection are British theater playbills from the 19th century and include specimens from Astley’s Royal Amphitheatre; Lyceum Theatre; Nottingham Empire; Royal Princess’s Theater; Surrey Theatre; Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden; Theatre Royal, Drury Lane; and others. Additionally, there are a very small number of American and foreign language playbills. Also included are five scrapbooks representing 19th and early 20th century theatre.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is organized in the following series: 1. Theatre Playbills; 2. Scrapbooks, Illustrations, and Photographs.
Goodman, Henry--Archives., d. 2012; Playbills--Collections.
Container List
- Playbills., circa 1762, 1786, 1790s, early 1800s-1865, 1871, early 1880s, 1895, early 1900s, and undated.
  Scope and Content
  The series consists of 18th, 19th, and 20th century British theatre playbills. The bulk of series are playbills from the 19th century and include both color and black and white specimens. The playbills represent performances from Astley’s Royal Amphitheatre; Lyceum Theatre; Nottingham Empire; Royal Princess’s Theater; Surrey Theatre; Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden; Theatre Royal, Drury Lane; and other theatres. Additionally included is one Russian language playbill, one French language playbill, and four items representing Yiddish theatre that are printed in English and what appears to be Hebrew. Among the many performers represented are Edwin Booth, William Cooke, Mr. Ducrow, Charles Kean, Edward Kean, Mr. C. Kemble, Madame Vestris, and Mr. Young.
  - Adelphi Theatre - Jack Robinson and His Monkey., 1839 Oct 18. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Additional listing: Dead Shot. Individuals listed: Mons. Gouffe, Mr. Jackson, Mr. Mercer, Mr. Ramsey, and others.
  - Alhambra Theatre - Don Juan., undated. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Color. Additional listings: Love in a Tub and On the Ice. Individuals listed: Madlle. Hoby, Madlle. Hooten, Signorina Legnani, Mr. G. Lupino, Madlle. Marie, Madame Roffey, M. Wagner, and others.
  - Alhambra - Tip-Toes., 1927 Apr 25. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    Color. Individuals listed: Teddy Fox, Billy Holland, Noel Leyland, Babs Valerie, Syd Walker, and others.
  - Astley's - Ducrow's Benefit., 1829 Sep 28. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Color. Individuals listed: Mr. Ducrow, Madame Merrimon, W.H. Williams, and others.
  - Astley's - The Fall of Sebastopol., 1855 Nov 19. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Individuals listed: Mr. J. Chaddock, William Cooke, James Holloway, Clementine Soullier, and others.
  - Astley's Amphitheatre - Surooj Seing., 1820 Jan 11. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Additional listing: Hunted Tailor. Individuals listed: Mrs. W. Barrymore, Miss Clarke, Mr. Slader, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - The Battle of the Amazons., 1848 Mar 27. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Individuals listed: Mr. T. Barry, Mr. G. Cooke, Mr. R. Smith, Mr. Widdicomb, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Battle of Waterloo., 1853 Sep 5. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Scope and Contents note
    Color. Individuals listed: Emily Cooke, Kate Cooke, William Cooke, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Bridge of GoldConda., 1852 Nov 1. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Color. Individuals listed: the Brothers Siegrist; Mr. Craddock, Mr. Danaville, Mr. Dolman, Miss Fenton, Mr. Johnson, Miss McLean, Mr. Maddocks, Miss Lydia Pearce, Mr. Rockerts, Mr. S. Smith, and company; and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Ducrow's Scenes in the Circle., 1827 Jul 30. (Bin 5, Folder 2)
    Individuals listed: Herr Benjamin, Herr Cline, Mr. Ducrow, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Equestrian Drama of Uncle Tom's Cabin., 1852 Nov 29. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Color. Individuals listed: Mons. and Mdlle. Lalande, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - The Great Fire of London., 1836 Apr 25. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Additional listing: Mr. Ducrow's New Scenes of the Circle and Grand Feats of Horsemanship. Individuals listed: Mr. Adams, Mr. Palmer, Mr. Widdicomb, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - The Golden Footed Steed., 1847 Jun 7. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Individuals listed: Mr. T. Barry, Mr. Barton, Mr. Johnson, Mr. Marwood, Mons. Plege, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Jibbenainosay., 1858 Mar 1. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Individuals listed: William Cooke, Mr. Croueste, Mr. J. Gee, Mdlle. Jennie, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Jupiter's Decree and the Fall of the Phaeton., 1853 Sep 26. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Color. Additional listing: Battle of Waterloo. Individuals listed: Mr. and Mrs. Bridges, Sig. Carlo and Sig. Francois, Kate Cooke, William Cooke, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - King Richard III., undated. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Photographs of illustration and playbill.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Merchant's Steed of Syracuse., 1846 Sep 7. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Color. Individuals listed: Morton Broo[k]es, J. Dale, J. Harwood, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Merchant's Steed of Syracuse., 1846 Sep 14. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Color.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Merchant's Steed of Syracuse., 1846 Oct 5. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Color. Individuals listed: Mr. T. Barry, Mrs. Batty, Herr Amidio Neopert, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Mooltan and Goojerat., 1849 May 28. (Box 8, Folder 2)
    Color. Individuals listed: Marie Macarte, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - Napoleon Bonaparte's Invasion of Russia., 1853 Nov 21. (Box 8, Folder 3)
    Color. Additional listing: Jupiter's Decree and the Fall of Phaeton. Individuals listed: Charles Adams, Alfred Cooke, Emily Cooke, William Cooke, Mdlle. Masota, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - O'Donogue., 1851 Feb 10. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Additional listing: Kenilworth. Individuals listed: Miss Caroline, Mr. Crowther, Mr. N.T. Hicks, Mons. Plasche, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - The Wars of the Jews., 1849 Feb 5. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Individuals listed: Mr. J. Bridges, Mr. James, Herr Jengler, Charles Johnson, and others.
  - Astley's Royal Amphitheatre - William Cooke's Annual Complimentary Benefit., 1858 Jun 17. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    Additional listing: The White Palfrey. Individuals listed: Sig. Agussi, William Cooke, Mr. Croueste, M. DeBerg, M. Thorne, and others.
  - Astley's Royal National Amphitheatre - Flight of Damon., 1841 May 17. (Box 5, Folder 3)
    Color. Individuals listed: Felix Carlo, Mr. and Madame Ducrow, Mr. Sloan, Mr. West, and others.
  - Casino Municipal de Wimereux - Triplepatte., 1907 Aug 23. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Individuals listed: M. Pierre Achard, Mme. Andree-Roustan, Mme. Marie Gallet, Mme. Marcelle Josset, Mlle. Blanche Marcel, and others.
  - Bower Saloon - Hofer the Tell of the Tyrol., undated. (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Color. Additional listing: The Six Finger'd Robber. Individuals listed: Mr. W. Attwood, Mr. H. Boville, Mr. J. Mathews, Mr. G. Nelson, and others.
  - [William] Cooke's Imperial Cirque (Moveable Architecture)., 1855 Nov 26. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Unrivalled Troupe of Equestrians and the Wonderful Trained Elephants. Individuals listed: Jane Cooke, Jas. Cooke, William Cooke, and others.
  - [William] Cooke's Royal Circus (North Street, Bristol)., 1850 Dec 9. (Box 8, Folder 10)
    Hearts of Oak or a Blue Jacket's Vicissitudes; Mazeppa and the Wild Horse of the Desert; and other events. Individuals listed: Alfred Cooke, William Cooke, J. K. Haberfield, and others.
  - Davidge's Royal Surrey Theatre - Ducrow's Grand Equestrian Fetes., undated. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Color. Individuals listed: Felix Carlo, Mr. Ducrow, Madame Ducrow, Mr. Graham, Signor Hillier, and others.
  - Davis's Royal Amphitheatre - Bonduca., [1823 Aug 21]. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Additional listing: Polichinel Vampire. Individuals listed: Mr. Collingbourne, Mr. Kirby, Monsieur Longuemare, Mrs. Makeen, and others.
  - Davis's Royal Amphitheatre - The Female Freebooter and the Mysterious Host., 1823 Apr 28. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Individuals listed: Mr. Darnley, Monsieur Longuemare, Mr. Ridgway, and others.
  - Davis's Royal Amphitheatre - The Siege of Londonderry and the Battle of the Boyne., 1823 Jul 14. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Additional listing: The Ghosts of Tom and Jerry. Individuals listed: Mr. Darnley, Mr. Davidge, Mr. Fillingham, Mr. Forster, Monsieur Longuemare, Mr. Slader, and others.
  - Davis's Royal Amphitheatre - Tom and Jerry., 1822 Apr 22. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Individuals listed: Mr. Baker, Mr. W. Barrymore, Mons. Decour, Mr. Slater, and others.
  - Drury Lane Theatre - The Minister and the Mercer., undated. (Box 6, Folder 11)
    Facsimile of prompt book pages. Research regarding staircase from the Enthoven Collecton at the Victoria and Albert Museum.
  - Effingham Saloon - Old London Bridge., 1850 Nov 4. (Bin 7, Folder 1)
    Color. Additional listings: Dumb Man of Manchester and Red Indian. Individuals listed: Marian Atkins, Mr. J. Chappell, Mr. R. Harrson, Oledan Tucker, and others.
  - Interior of Guildhall - London By Night., undated. (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Additional listings: The Bohemian Girl, Fra Diavolo, and other events. Individuals listed: Mr. Buckstone, Mr. Farquarhson, Mr. Manvers, Mrs. Sims Reeves, Mr. Weiss, Madame Weiss, and others.
  - London Palladium - Coming Attractions., 1953. (Box 6, Folder 12)
    Color. Bud Abbott and Lou Costello; Billy Daniels with Benny Payne; Bob Hope; Franie Laine; Dean Martin and Jerry Lewis; Guy Mitchell; and Kay Starr.
  - Lyceum Theatre - Guy Mannering., 1849 Jul 11. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Color. Additional listing: Used Up. Individuals listed: Miss Cushman, Mr. Parselle, and others.
  - Lyceum Theatre - King Lear photograph of illustration., undated. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Lyceum Theatre - Love in a Village., 1848 Jul 11. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Color. Additional listings: A Speaking Likeness and A Rough Diamond. Individuals listed: Mr. W. Harrison, Charles Mathews, and others.
  - Lyceum Theatre - Othello., [1881 May 28]. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Color. Individuals listed: Edwin Booth, Henry Irving, Ellen Terry, and others.
  - Lyceum Theatre - Poor Pillicoddy., 1848 Jul 28. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Color. Additional listings: Blue Beard; Theseus and Ariadne. Individuals listed: Mr. Buckstone, Mr. H. Hall, Miss Howard, Miss Lee, Miss Marshall, and others.
  - Metropolitan - Old Time Variety., [no year] May 24. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Color. Terry Bartlett with Terry Durham; Kitty Gillow; Glyn Hale; Jay Kay; Norah Milne; Morris and Cowley; Betty Morton; Harry Orchid; George Van Dusen; and Vernon Sisters.
  - New City Theatre - The Merchant of Venice., 1831 May 21. (Box 6, Folder 9)
    Additional listings: A Roland for an Oliver and No.1 (Or, The Hackney Coachman). Individuals listed: Edmund Kean, John Reeves, Mr. W.H. Williams, and others.
  - New Holborn Theatre Royal - Flying Scud., 1867 Mar 4. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Additional listing: My Turn Next. Individuals listed: Mr. Belmore, Mr. E. Garden, Mr. G. Neville, Mr. Willmott, and others.
  - Nottingham Empire., 1931 Dec 28. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Color. Bob and Alf Pearson; Bow Bells; Bu-Bu the Wonder Chimpanzee; Henri Benito and His san Marino Accordion Syncopators; the Lington Sisters; Carr Lynn; Nat Mills and Bobbie; Ella Retford; and Ethel Revnell and Gracie West.
  - Nottingham Empire - Carnival Time., 1932 Feb 29. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Color. Additional listing: Bow Bells. Individuals listed: Olive Fox, Clarkson Rose, Joe Young, and others.
  - Nottingham Empire- The Jazz Parade., 1930 Nov 24. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Color. Additional listing: Sons O' Guns. Individuals listed: Arthur Lucan, Kitty McShane, Eric Randolph, and others.
  - Nottingham Empire - More Splinters., 1932 Feb 8. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Color. Additional listing: Bow Bells. Individuals listed: Hall Jones, Andy Paterson, Leslie Pearce, Reg. Stone, and others.
  - Nottingham Empire - Potted Personalities., 1930 Jul 14. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Color. Additional listing: Sons O' Guns. Individuals Listed: Elsie Keene, Madge Kennedy, Billy Merson, Bert Weston, and others.
  - Nottingham Empire - Sophie Tucker (at the piano Ted Shapiro)., 1931 Apr 27. (Box 8, Folder 4)
    Color. Additional listings: Benedetti Brothers; Bernard and Rich; Jack Buchanan; Geo. D'Orrmonde; Charles Jones and Victor Thomas; The Rego Twins; and Rose Perfect.
  - Olympia de Londres - Bolossy Kiralfy., undated. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Palladium Oxford Circus., 1929 Jul 29. (Box 7, File 3)
    Color. Harry Burns; Geo. D'Ormonde; De Groot; Derickson and Brown; George Herman; Mandis Trio; Mitchell and Durant; Lily Morris; and Payne and Hilliard.
  - Pavilion - Ambrose Gwinett., 1848 Aug 28. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Additional listing: Wilful Murder. Individuals listed: Eugene Cony, E. F. Taylor, and others.
  - Pavilion Theatre - Civilization., 1860 Jun 20. (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Additional listings: Hamlet; King of the Commons; The Lord and Peasant; and others. Individuals listed: James Anderson, Miss Marriott, and others.
  - Prince of Wales Theatre - Ixion., 1864 Feb 22. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Color. Additional listing: Miriam's Crime. Individuals listed: Lionel Brough, S. Cowell, Felix Rogers, Jenny Wilmore, and others.
  - Princess's Theatre - After Dark., 1868 Dec 14. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Additional listing: Master Jones's Birthday. Individuals listed: Rebecca Isaacs, Dominick Murray, Mr. J.G. Shore, and others.
  - Princess's Theatre - Macbeth., 1871 Jun 5. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Additional listings: The Belles of the Kitchen and Clandestine Marriage. Individuals listed: Mr. Phelps, Fawdon Vokes, Fred Vokes, Miss J. Vokes, Miss R. Vokes, Miss V. Vokes, and others.
  - Princess's Theatre - The Octoroon., 1868 Feb 10. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Additional listing: Arrah-na-Pogue. Individuals listed: Dion Boucicault, John S. Clarke, and others.
  - Royal Amphitheatre and Theatre of Novelties., undated. (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Acrobatic Revels; Aerial Bicycle feats; Mdlle. E. Albrecht; Astounding Mid-Air feats; Marie Barnum and J.H. Ryley; Messrs. Orkins and Bell; Louise Rosalie; and The Three Stars of the North.
  - Royal Amphitheatre (Astley's) - The Burmese War., 1826 Apr 10. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Individuals listed: Mr. Gomersal, Mrs. Gomersal, Mr. Lawrence, and others.
  - Royal Amphitheatre (Astley's) - Gil Blas de Santillane., 1821 Jun 26. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Individuals listed: Mr. Avery, Mr. W. Barrymore, Mr. Cowel, and others.
  - Royal Amphitheatre (Astley's) - Spain and Portugal., 1827 Apr 23. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Individuals listed: Mr. Amherest, Mr. Ducrow, Mr. Pritchard, Mr. Wilkinson, and others.
  - Royal Lyceum Theatre - Faust., undated. (Box 6, Folder 13)
    Color. Additional listing: The Merchant of Venice. Individuals listed: Mr. Laurence Irving, Mark Paton, Mr. T. Reynolds, Mr. H.B. Stanford, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - photographs representing illustrations of Charles Kean (2 items)., undated. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    One item may represent Macbeth.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - The Fool's Revenge., undated. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Additional listing: Othello. Individuals listed: John Beauchamp, Edwin Booth, Mr. F. Charles, William Redmund, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - Hamlet., undated. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Additional listing: Thrice Married. Individuals listed: Mr. Fetcher, Miss Reynolds, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - King Lear., [no year] Feb 14. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Individuals listed: Edwin Booth, Mr. Chamberlain, Mr. Stirling, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - Macbeth., 1853 May 27. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Additional listing: Black-Eyed Susan. Individuals listed: Mr J. F. Cathcart, Mr. F. Cooke, Miss Hasting, Charles Kean, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - The Merchant of Venice., [1881 Mar]. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Individuals listed: Edwin Booth, Mr. W. Redmund, John Ryder, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - Midsummer Night's Dream., 1856 Oct 15. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Additional listing: Pizarro. Individuals listed: Charles Kean, Mr. Raymond, Mr. Ryder, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - Othello., [1881 Jan 22]. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Individuals listed: John Beauchamp, Edwin Booth, Mr. Chamberlin, John Ryder, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - Richelieu., [1880 Nov 27]. (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Additional listings: Othello and The Fool's Revenge. Individuals listed: Mr. P.C. Beverley, Edwin Booth, Edmund Leathes, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - The Streets of London., 1864 Nov 21. (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Additional listing: Born to Good Luck. Individuals listed: Mr. Brooke, Mr. M. Mellon, Mr. J.W. Ray, Mr. W.R. Robins, and others.
  - Royal Princess's Theatre - The Tempest., undated. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Additional listings: A Case of Conscience and Richard the Second. Individuals listed: David Fisher, Charles Kean, Rose Leclercq, and others.
  - Royal Queen's Theatre - Hamlet, Prince of Denmark., 1862 Nov 3. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    Color. Additional listings: Macbeth' The Rifle and How to Use it; and other events. Individuals listed: James R. Anderson, Margaret Eburne, H. Widdcombe, and others.
  - Royal Surrey Theatre - The Earl of Poverty., 1838 Feb 12. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Additional listings: Fate of Andre, and other events. Individuals listed: Mr. Dale, Mr. Dillon, Mr. Goldsmith, Mr. E.F. Saville, and others.
  - Royal Surrey Theatre - King Holiday., 1859 Dec 26. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Color. Additional listing: The Fugitive. Individuals listed: John Lauri, Louisa Lauri, Mr. Vollaire, Miss A Wood, and others.
  - Royal Surrey Theatre - Law of the Land., 1837 Sep 25. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Additional listing: Bedouin Arabs. Individuals listed: Mr. Cooper, Mr. Dale, Mr. Elvin, Mr. Goldsmith, and others.
  - Royal Surrey Theatre - Wapping Old Stairs., 1837 Nov 20. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Additional listings: Whistler, Skeleton Witness, and others. Individuals listed: Mr. Dillion, Mr. Elvin, Mr. Green, Dibdin Pitt, Mr. E.F. Saville, and others.
  - Royal Vauxhall Gardens., [1846] Sep 4. (Box 7, Box 6)
    Color. Grand Concert with composer and musical director Alexander Lee, The American Brothers, Tournaire's Equestrian Troup, and other acts.
  - Russian playbill., undated. (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Annotated Revisor Government Inspector; Gogol; and Velski [Balauff].
  - Sadler's Wells - Hamlet., 1853 Feb 10. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Additional listing: Whittington and His Cat. Individuals listed: Mr. Barrett, George Bennett, Mr. Phelps, and others.
  - Sadler's Wells - Hamlet., 1858 Nov 27. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    Additional listings: Henry the Eighth; My Old Luck; The Stranger and the Comedy of Errors; and other events. Individuals listed: Mr. Haywell, Mr. Phelps, Mr. J.W. Ray, Mr. Seyton, and others.
  - St. Mary's Hall - Hamilton's Excursions., undated. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    Color. Individuals listed: Mr. and Mrs. Hayes, Reed Larwell, and others.
  - Standard Theatre - Bar Kochva (Or, The Son of the Star)., 1895 Dec 14. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Color. Hebrew and English. Individuals listed: Madame Pront, Mr. Pont, Mr. Natanson, Mr. Zablinski, and others.
  - Standard Theatre - Fall of Jerusalem: Hebrew Opera in 5 acts by Latiner., 1895. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Color. Hebrew and English. Individuals listed: Mr. Finegold, Mr. Goldsmitt, Mr. Natanson, Mr. Waxman, and others.
  - Standard Theatre - La Sulamita (Or, The Daughter of Bethlehem)., 1895 Nov 30. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Color. Hebrew and English. Individuals listed: Madame Pront, Mr. Pont, Mr. Wallerstein, Mr. Zablinski, and others.
  - Standard Theatre - Melitz Yoshar (Or, Rabbi Joselmann)., 1895 Dec 20. (Box 6, Folder 23)
    Separated Material
    Color. Hebrew and English. Individuals listed: Mr. Feinberg, Mr. Pront, Mr. Rosenfeld, Mr. Wallerstein, and others.
  - Surrey Theatre - Cinderella., 1851 Jun 21. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Additional listings: La Sonnambula, Der Freischutz, and others. Individuals listed: Mr. Borrani, Mr. H. Corri, Signora Fenelle, Miss P. Horton, Herr Kuchler, Miss A. Norman, Miss Poole, Mr. T. German Reed, Mr. C. Romer, Mr. Travers, and others
  - Surrey Theatre - Esmeralda., 1834 Apr 28. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Additional listings: Hunter of the Alps; Baron Trenck; and The Heart of London. Individuals listed: Mr. C. Hill, Dibdin Pitt, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Surrey Theatre - Jonathan Bradford., 1853 Aug 15. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Additional listings: Lord Mayor's Fool and Returned Pirate. Individuals listed: Mr. C. Hill, Dibdin Pitt, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Surrey Theatre - Law of the Land., undated. (Box 5, Folder 11)
    Color. Caricatures of six scenes.
  - Surrey Theatre - Napoleon, the Victim of Ambition., 1831 May 30. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Additional listing: Sharps, Flats, and Naturals. Individuals listed: Mr. C. Hill, Mr. C. Poole, Mr. Young, and others.
  - Theatre Royal - The Gamester., [no year] Nov 26. (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Additional listing: Raymond and the Agnesi. Individuals listed: Mr. Conway, Mr. Foot, and Mr. Younger.
  - Theatre Royal - Kathleen Mavourneen., 1866 Nov 13-17. (Box 8, Folder 6)
    Color. Additional listing: Mazourka. Individuals listed: Pauline Burette, Mary Smith, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Birmingham - Coriolanus., 1842 Jan 25. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Additional listings: The Deserter and The Secret. Individuals listed: Mr. Munro, Mr. and Miss Vandenhoff, Mr. Wilson, Mr. Wyndham, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Birmingham - Loan of a Lover., 1844 Aug 2. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    Additional listings: Platter versus Clatter, Grist to the Mill, and The Young Actress. Individuals listed: Charles Mathews, Fanny Ternan, Madame Vestris, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Artaxerxes., 1816 Oct 29. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Additional listings: The Broken Sword; The Careful Servant and Careless Master; and Lodoiska. Individuals listed: Miss Carew, Mr. Duruset, Mr. Sinclair, Miss Stephens, Mr. Treby, and others.
  - Theatre Royal, Covent-Garden - Beauty and the Beast., 1841 May 6. (Box 5, Folder 13)